<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Fromage &amp; Programming</title>
    <description>A summary of personnal courses/projects providing cheat sheet to help people starting to program in general.</description>
    <link>http://localhost:5000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:5000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
      <item>
        <title>Torchlurk</title>
        <description>
          
          Don't hesitate to visit the official Torchlurk's website or github repo! Description Torchlurk is a python library allowing you to easily visualize what your sequential CNN has learned by providing various feature such as Grad-CAM, saliency maps or filter visualization directly in a notebook or by serving it on a...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 10 Oct 2010 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:5000/2010-10-10-torchlurk/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:5000/2010-10-10-torchlurk/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>EmoDB Speech Classification</title>
        <description>
          
          You can access the presentation here and the github repo here Introduction EmoDB, as known as Berlin Database of Emotional Speech, is a dataset presenting short speeches of 6 types of emotions in german. (anger, happiness, fear, disgust, neutral and boredom) The project, made in the context of a one-week...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 10 Oct 2010 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:5000/2010-10-10-speech/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:5000/2010-10-10-speech/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Network for Mouse Genetics</title>
        <description>
          
          In collaboration with Raphael Reis, Gianni Giusto and Lucas ZweiliYou can access the full data story here Introduction Wikipedia describes the phenotype as the composite of the organism’s observable characteristics or traits. (…) An organism’s phenotype results from two basic factors: the expression of an organism’s genetic code, or its...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 10 Oct 2010 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:5000/2010-10-10-mouse_gen/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:5000/2010-10-10-mouse_gen/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Yet Another MNIST classification project</title>
        <description>
          
          You can access the github repository here Introduction The present repository aims at presenting (yet another..) MNIST classification method, but tries to avoid state of the art pretrained models and rather implement the following features, as a deepL challenge and in order to assess whether Genetic Algorithm perform as well...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 10 Oct 2010 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:5000/2010-10-10-mnist/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:5000/2010-10-10-mnist/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>CheapTorch</title>
        <description>
          
          You can access the github repo here and the report here Introduction After Facebook started storing Zetabytes of various private data about their users (among it H24 4k video recording of the users cats) a unique bug in history destroyed all instances of the Autograd Framework. Luckily, some coders were...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 10 Oct 2010 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:5000/2010-10-10-minideepl/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:5000/2010-10-10-minideepl/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Higg Boson Competition</title>
        <description>
          
          In collaboration with Gianni Giusto and Maxime EparsYou can access the github repo Introduction As part of the CS-433 master course of Machine Learning, an AI crowd competition took was organized for the students: the goal consisted in developing ourself the methods used such as KFold cross-validation, stochastic gradient descent,...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 10 Oct 2010 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:5000/2010-10-10-higg/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:5000/2010-10-10-higg/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>C++ Multithreaded Coencapsulation</title>
        <description>
          Lab. of Systems Biology and Genetics (EPFL) - 
          Introduction The goal of the project consisted in coencapsulation of micro-beads of RNA primers with cells into a single drop of lysis buffer using microships: both the cells and the beads would flow through channels A and B respectively. Microship used for coencapsulation: A. Cell channel B. Bead channel C....
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 10 Oct 2010 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:5000/2010-10-10-coencaps/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:5000/2010-10-10-coencaps/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>From Adam to W</title>
        <description>
          
          In collaboration with Jonathan Besomi and Stefano HuberYou can access the full data story here Github Repo AdamW reference article Introduction The project consists in an overview and performance comparison of the AdamW optimizer over the classically used Adam on 3 state of the art datasets in order to assess...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 10 Oct 2010 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:5000/2010-10-10-adamw/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:5000/2010-10-10-adamw/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Data Awareness Dunnhumby dataset</title>
        <description>
          
          In collaboration with Raphael Reis, Daniel Pechao and Jérôme LüscherYou can access the full data story here Introduction We proposed an in-depth analysis of the complete-journey dunnhumby dataset: a file gathering information about consumer behaviors and demographic information for the dunnhumby supermarket chain. Implementation Since more than 90% of our...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 10 Oct 2010 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:5000/2010-10-10-ada/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:5000/2010-10-10-ada/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A ML approach to determine chemical shifts in NMR</title>
        <description>
          Lab. of Computational Science and Modeling (EPFL) - 
          In collaboration with Gianni Giusto and Maxime Epars You can access the full report here Introduction Nuclear magnetic resonance (NMR) spectroscopy is a method used to determine the chemical structure of a molecule based on the principle of the resonance frequency: any nuclear spin in a given structure depends on...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 10 Oct 2010 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:5000/2010-10-10-NMR/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:5000/2010-10-10-NMR/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Machine Learning Competition ETH</title>
        <description>
          
          In collaboration with Marijn Van der MeerYou can access the github repo Introduction As part of the Bachelor Machine Learning course at ETH, we participated in a competition using the various techniques seen during the course. This competition consisted of 2 training datasets both having 139 features: a labelled one...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 10 Oct 2010 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:5000/2010-10-10-MLproj_ETH/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:5000/2010-10-10-MLproj_ETH/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>List of Courses</title>
        <description>
          
          This section aims at presenting a non-exhaustive list of the Data Science-related courses that I followed untill and including now during my cursus at EPFL and ETH. Current Courses Fall 2020 Optionnal project in Data Science Prof. West: Analysis of the emojis semantic representation with an NLP approach for various...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 10 Oct 2010 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:5000/2010-10-10-courses/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:5000/2010-10-10-courses/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Vallgrotte</title>
        <description>
          
          

 
 
 



  
   
  
  
  
    
  
  
  



  
    
  



        </description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 10 Oct 2010 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:5000/2010-10-10-vallgrotte/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:5000/2010-10-10-vallgrotte/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Brie Bleu</title>
        <description>
          
          

 
 
 



  
   
  
  
  
    
  
  
  
  
    
  
  



  
    
  



        </description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 10 Oct 2010 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:5000/2010-10-10-mottens/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:5000/2010-10-10-mottens/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Coulomier</title>
        <description>
          
          

 
 
 



  
   
  
  
  



  
    
  



        </description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 10 Oct 2010 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:5000/2010-10-10-coulomier/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:5000/2010-10-10-coulomier/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Brin d'Aunour</title>
        <description>
          
          

 
 
 



  
   
  
  
  
    
  
  
  



  
    
  



        </description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 10 Oct 2010 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:5000/2010-10-10-brindaunour/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:5000/2010-10-10-brindaunour/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Brie Bleu</title>
        <description>
          
          

 
 
 



  
   
  
  
  
    
  
  
  
  
    
  
  



  
    
  



        </description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 10 Oct 2010 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:5000/2010-10-10-briebrebis/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:5000/2010-10-10-briebrebis/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Brie Bleu</title>
        <description>
          
          

 
 
 



  
   
  
  
  
    
  
  
  
  
    
  
  



  
    
  



        </description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 10 Oct 2010 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:5000/2010-10-10-briebleu/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:5000/2010-10-10-briebleu/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Brie à l'ail des ours</title>
        <description>
          
          Fromage présentant une odeur crémante, arrière d’ail des ours, dominance ail des ours, très frais tend vers l’amertume sans pour autant l’atteindre vraiment évoque l’attaqeu de la truffe mais n’explose pas au nez fondant, similaire au beurre croûte très fine, imperceptible a la mastication un peu d’étable à l’odeur ,...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 10 Oct 2010 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:5000/2010-10-10-brieADO/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:5000/2010-10-10-brieADO/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Mottens</title>
        <description>
          
          

 
 
 



  
   
  
  
  
    
  
  
  
  
    
  
  



  
    
  



        </description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 10 Oct 2010 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:5000/2010-10-10-bottens/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:5000/2010-10-10-bottens/</guid>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
